A Finding Aid to the Burt Chernow Papers, 1930-2002, in the Archives of American Art AAA.cherburt
Archives of American Art
- Research Material for Christo and Jeanne-Claude: A Biography, 1930-2002; Series 1; 17.1 Linear feet Boxes 1-17, 23, OV 24
  - Sound Recordings, 1977-1997; 1.2; 3 Linear feet Boxes 3-5
    - Interviews with Other Subjects, by Name (Box 4)
      - Imants Tillers, on Wrapped Coast, 1989 May 22; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 235 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 6)
      - Harry Torczyner, 1993 August 6; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 99 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 7)
      - Harry Torczyner, 1993 August 16; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 194 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 8)
      - Audrey Tsui (Box 4)
      - Christian Tröster (Box 4)
        See Interviews with Other Subjects by Project, Wrapped Reichstag, 1995 June 19-20.
      - Marina Vaizey (Box 4)
      - Jan Van Der Marck (Box 4)
        See 1981 Interview under Christo Lectures and Interviews by Others.
      - Martin Visser, 1993 April 16; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 159 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 9)
      - Herbert and Dorothy Vogel, 1990 October 4; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 182 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 10)
      - Wolfgang Volz (Box 4)
      - Jon Voss, 1991 January 2; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 241, 242 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 11)
        Part 2 found on tape with part 1 of Carole Weisweiller interview.
      - Andreas Vowinckel (Box 4)
        See Interviews with Other Subjects by Project, Wrapped Reichstag, 1995 June 19.
      - Sam Weiner (Box 4)
        Interview found on same tape as Jeanne-Claude interview of 1995 March 30, filed with Interviews with Christo and Jeanne-Claude.
      - Carole Weisweiller, 1991 January 4; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 242, 192 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 12)
        Part 1 of interview found on tape with part 2 of interview with Jan Voss.
      - Masahiko Yanagi, in Berlin, 1995 June 17; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 132 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 13)
      - Mitko Zagoroff, 1988 June 14; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 103 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 14)
      - Anna and Jurgen Zech, on Wrapped Reichstag (1995), 1995 June 25; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 130 (Box 4, Folder 6, Item 15)
    - Interviews with Other Subjects, by Project (Box 5)
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), 1985 September 19; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 270 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 1)
        Tom Golden, Josy Kraft, Ann Chernow, Jim Fuller, and Michael Cullen
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), 1985 September 20; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 278, 287 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 2)
        Toni Buringer, Albert Maysles, Karyn Allen, Fritz de Knegt, Karen Kalish, David Johnson, and Cyril Christo
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), 1985 September 21; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 273, 272 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 3)
        Bob Adams, Annlee Juda, Marina Vaizey, Emil De Hantsetters, Serge DeBloe, and Klaus Rosen
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), 1985 September 22; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 276, 281 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 4)
        John Thompson, Jacob Baal-Teshuva, Ted Dougherty, and Christo.
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), 1985 September 23; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 279, 286 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 5)
        David Juda, David Maysles, Lennart Preutz, John Kaldor, Jacob Baal-Techuva, Precilda de Guillebon, and comments by Burt Chernow
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), 1985 September 24; 3 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 275, 274, 271 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 6)
        Christo working process, Keiko Murata (interpreter), Mr. and Mrs. Kazuhiko Satani, Torsten Lilju, Burt Chernow notes on Pont Neuf reception, Holly and Horace Solomon, Yusuke Nakahara, Vahé Aprahamian, reading Cyril's poem.
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), 1985 September 25; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 277, 280 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 7)
        Carl Floch, Linde, Wolfgang Volz, Joe Fleming
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), 1985 September 26-27; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 284, 288 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 8)
        Harrison Rivera Terreaux, Bill Crimmins, Burt Chernow comments, Ted Dougherty parts 2 and 3, Michael Cullen, Paul Jenkins, and Georges Fall.
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped (1985), 1985 September 28; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 283, 269 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 9)
        Carline Bouilhet, Burt Chernow comments, "Carl Andre quote," Christo with Chernow and British collector, and Paul Jenkins.
      - Umbrellas (1991) (Box 5)
        - In Japan, 1991 October 7; 1 Sound cassettes tapes numbered 201 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 1)
          Conversation with Christo, Jeanne-Claude, and Simon about delaying Umbrellas blossoming; Christo speaking with workers in Japan.
        - In Japan, 1991 October 10; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 198 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 2)
          Notes on Umbrellas, Pepe Jose Acevas.
        - In Japan, 1991 October 7; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 160 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 3)
          Translator Setsvko Shibata, welcome reception, press conference, Maysles talk, Michael Cullen. On the same cassette as California interview with Michael Cullen.
        - Michael Cullen, in California, 1991 October 13; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 160 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 4)
        - In California, 1991 October 8; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 197 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 5)
          Ann Chernow interviews local waitress and two crew chiefs for Umbrellas.
        - In California, 1991 October 8; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 197 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 6)
          Thomas Garver and Audrey Tsui.
        - In California, 1991 October; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 196; poor sound quality (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 7)
          Interviews with visitors at California installment of Umbrellas, and with Dennis McCarthy
      - Wrapped Reichstag (1995) (Box 5)
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), Berlin Notes by Burt Chernow, 1995 June 16-27; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 264 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 8)
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), 1995 June 17; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 124 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 9)
          Leni Chevasson, Jonita Davenport
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), 1995 June 18; 3 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 136, 135, 134 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 10)
          Roland Specker, Michael Cullen, and Jacob Baal-Teshuva.
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), 1995 June 19; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 119 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 11)
          Kathrine Donnelly of the Goethe Institute of Washington, DC, Jacob Baal-Teshuva, Christian Tröster, Andreas Vowinckel.
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), Press Conference with Christo and Jeanne-Claude in Berlin, 1995 June 19; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 128, 127 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 12)
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), 1995 June 20; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 125 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 13)
          Berlin notes, Albert Maysles, Dale Chihuly, Leslie Jackson, Christian Tröster.
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), 1995 June 20-21; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 121 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 14)
          Swana Morenz, Ann Chernow notes, Monica Dernhoff, Didi Javacheff notes, Mitko notes, man on the street interviews.
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), 1995 June 21; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 123 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 15)
          Wolfgang Buggenhagen, Mike Cullen, and Timothy Garton Ash.
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), 1995 June 21-23; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 120 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 16)
          Notes, man on the street interviews, John Thompson, Lucia Thompson.
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), 1995 June 22-25; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 122 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 17)
          Berlin notes, Television coverage in German.
        - Wrapped Reichstag (1995), Katrin Specker, 1995 June 23; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 131 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 1)
    - Christo Lectures and Interviews by Others (Box 5)
      - Christo Lecture at the Young Presidents Organization meeting in Hawaii, 1977; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 55 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 2)
      - Christo interview by Ann Stubbs, 1978; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 61 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 3)
      - Christo and Jock Truman Lectures at University of Minnesota, 1979; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 64 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 4)
      - Christo Interview by Maurice Tuchman, 1979 August 17; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 69 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 5)
        Interview conducted in relation to 1980 LACMA exhibition, "The Avant-Garde in Russia, 1910-1930: New Perspectives"; see Sound Recordings, Documentary.
      - Interview with Christo by Joan Gassisi-Rubin, 1980 August; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 54, 53 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 6)
      - Christo Lecture at Aldrich Museum, introduced by Burt Chernow, 1981 July 19
        - Question and Answer Session, 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 202, "Unedited master" (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 7)
        - Introduction and Question and Answer Session, 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 55, 203; "Edited" (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 8)
      - Interview with Christo by Lauree Poulet, 1982 January 24; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 50 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 9)
      - Christo interview by Robert Kirkland of Newsweek, 1982 April 28; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 59 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 10)
      - Christo interview by Frank Gettings, 1983 June 27; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 58 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 11)
        Found on the same cassette as Susan Stamberg "All Things Considered" interview.
      - Christo interview by Susan Stamberg on "All Things Considered", 1984 May 14; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 58 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 12)
        Found on the same cassette as Frank Gettings interview.
      - Christo interview by Anton Rush for Blitz Magazine article, 1983 October 13; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 63 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 13)
      - Christo Interview by Barry Farber on "The Barry Farber Show", 1983; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 62 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 14)
      - Christo interview with Douglas Brooks for the magazine "Belief in Action", 1984 January 21; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 62 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 15)
      - Christo Lecture at Sogetsu Hall, Tokyo, 1984 April 5; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 65 (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 16)
      - Christo Lecture at the Hirshhorn Museum, 1984 May 13; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 52 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 1)
      - Christo and Atanas Slavov, 1984 August 17; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 60; "mostly Bulgaria commentator and brief Christo in English" (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 2)
      - Christo Lecture to Westport Arts Council, introduced by Burt Chernow, 1984 August 24; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 204, 205 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 3)
      - National Arts Club Artist of the Year Award, 1992 January 22; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 97 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 4)
        With Agnes Gund, Grace Glueck, David Bourdon, and Albert Maysles
      - Christo Lecture at Cooper Union on Wrapped Reichstag, 1994 April 25; 2 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 225, 224 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 5)
      - Christo Lecture at Pratt Institute, 1995 March 14; 4 Sound cassettes tapes labeled 217, 216, 215, 214 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 6)
        Tapes 1 and 4 contain Chernow's conversation with Christo and Jeanne-Claude before and after the lecture.
      - Press Conference on Wrapped Reichstag with Christo and Jeanne-Claude in Berlin (Box 5)
    - Lecture by Jan Van Der Marck on Christo, 1981 November 21; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 68 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 8)
    - Interviews of Burt and Ann Chernow (Box 5)
      - On the Pont Neuf Wrapped for the CBC, 1985 September 19; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 263 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 9)
      - On the Wrapped Reichstag with Cynthia Scudder of WEZN, 1995 September 17; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 71 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 10)
    - Music (Box 5)
      - Song Written in Protest of Surrounded Islands, 1983 May; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 186 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 11)
      - Umbrella Song, circa 1991; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 195 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 12)
    - Documentary, The Avant-Garde in Russia, 1984 December 6; 1 Sound cassettes tape labeled 49 (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 13)
  - Transcripts and Subject files, 1959-1998; 1.3; 2 Linear feet Boxes 6-7
    Transcripts for the Christos are arranged chronologically, followed by transcripts and subject files for other subjects, arranged alphabetically or by project. Most of the transcripts for Christo's lectures, as well as interviews of the Christos conducted by others, are filed at the end of the series, although some are integrated into the unedited Christo transcripts. Note that while most of the interviews with both the Christos are filed with the Christo transcripts, a single interview conducted 8/16/95 with both of them is filed with the Jeanne-Claude transcripts. Additional material related to Arman is found in series 2, Other Writings.
    Series contains mainly files for the interview subjects found in series 1.2, including the Christos, their associates, containing transcripts and sometimes other materials related to the interview subject, such as correspondence, photographs, clippings, and other printed material. Also found are files for individuals who were not interviewed by Chernow, or whose interviews were not recorded, containing research or other material. Transcripts of Christo's lectures and interviews of Chrsito by others that were collected by Chernow are also found in this series.
    Transcripts for Burt Chernow's interviews with Christo and Jeanne are represented in two separate files, one containing interviews with Christo or both the Christos, and another for interviews with Jeanne-Claude interviewed alone. Each set of these transcripts has unedited and edited versions. The unedited file contains transcripts of all interviews in chronological order, as well as notes from unrecorded conversations, with continuous pagination for the entire set created by Chernow. The edited file contains photocopies of selected pages from these transcripts, with all but the portion used by Chernow in his writing crossed out. Note that many of the transcripts throughout the series contain notes summarizing portions of the session, so transcripts in this series are not a comprehensive record of the interviews found in series 1.2.
    A large number of photocopies of photographs and exhibition checklists with prices are found with Christo transcripts from 1992. Transcripts throughout the file also include scattered copies of items related to matters discussed in the interviews.
    Transcripts and subject files for subjects other than the Christos are in individual folders by the interview subject's name or by project. Files for Arman, Ray Johnson, and Mary Bauermeister are particularly rich with additional research and other material. A file of edited transcripts also exists for this portion of the series. Transcripts of Christo lectures and interviews of Christo by others are filed chronologically at the end of the series. A file of tyepscript notes regarding questions for interviews is also found at the end of the series.
    Note that not all of the transcripts found in this series have recordings in series 1.2. Transcripts and subject files with no corresponding recorded interview in series 1.2 include Lourdes Castro, Paul Cummings, Sam Hunter, James Juszczyk, Nam June Paik, Dieter Rosenkranz, Satcho Todorov, and John Weber, among others.
    - Christo Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Christo Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Christo Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Christo Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Christo Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Christo Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Christo Interview Transcripts, Edited, 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Christo Interview Transcripts, Edited, 1990-1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Jeanne-Claude Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Jeanne-Claude Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Jeanne-Claude Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Jeanne-Claude Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Jeanne-Claude Interview Transcripts, Unedited, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Jeanne-Claude Interview Transcripts, Edited, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Jeanne-Claude Interview Transcripts, Edited, 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Jeanne-Claude Interview Transcripts, Edited, 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Other Subjects, By Name, Unedited (Box 6)
      - "Pepe" Jose Aceves, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Bob Adams, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Karyn Allen, 1985
      - Lawrence Alloway, 1986-1990 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Ed Anderson, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Vahé and Berj Aprahamian, 1985-1991 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Arman, 1987-1995 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Timothy Garton Ash, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Jacob Baal-Teshuva, 1985-1995 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Edith Bass, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Mary Bauermeister, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - René Bértholo, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Peter Bonnier, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Carline Bouilhet, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - David Bourdon, 1985-1994 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Wolfgang Buggenhagen, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Toni Buringer, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Giovanni Camuffo, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - Leo Castelli, 1986-1992 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Lourdes Castro, 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - Ann Chernow, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Ann and Burt Chernow, Canadian Broadcasting Company Interview, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Leni Chevasson, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - Dale Chihuly, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - Cyril Christo, 1983-1996 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - Henry Cora, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - Bill Crimmons, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Mike Cullen, 1985-1996 (Box 6, Folder 44)
      - Paul Cummings, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 45)
      - Jonita Davenport, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - Serge DeBloe, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - Suzanne Delehanty, 1987-1996 (Box 6, Folder 48)
      - Monica Dernhoff, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 49)
      - Kathryn Donnelly, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - Ted Dougherty, 1985-1991 (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - Rosa Erdman, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - Joe Fleming, 1985-1997 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - Carl Floch, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - Jim Fuller, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - Tom Garver, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - John Gibson, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - Grace Gleuck, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 58)
      - Ellen Goheen, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 59)
      - Tom Golden, 1985-1996 (Box 6, Folder 60)
      - Gianfranco Gorgoni, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 61)
      - Alexandra Gerard de Guillebon and Joyce-May Henery, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 62)
      - Norbert de Guillebon, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 63)
      - Precilda de Guillebon, circa 1983-1990 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Other Subjects, by Name, Unedited (Box 7)
      - Agnes Gund, 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Raymond Hains, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Emil De Hantsetters, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Joyce-May Henery, 1986-1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        Contains photographs of early portraits of Henery created by Christo.
      - Lynn Hershman, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Arnold Herstand, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Scott Hodes, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Sam Hunter, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Catherine Issert, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Sidney Janis, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Anani Javacheff, 1986-1998 (Box 7, Folder 11)
        Contains photographs of Javacheff family visit to the U.S., showing Anani, Didi, and Vlado Javacheff as well as Burt Chernow, photocopies of passports, and letters. Also contains Chernow's notes showing Javacheff family tree, a diagram of the family home, and a map of the family's village.
      - Didi Javacheff, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Stefan Javacheff, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Paul Jenkins and Georges Fall, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - David Johnson, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Ray Johnson, 1977-1995 (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
        Contains photocopied letters from Johnson to Christo, some original mail art by Johnson, and exhibition catalogs and a magazine article.
      - Annalee Juda, 1985-1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - David Juda, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - James Juszczyk, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - John Kaldor, 1985-1995 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Karen Kadish, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Allan Kaprow, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 23)
        Contains research material on Kaprow.
      - Ivan Karp, 1986-1994 (Box 7, Folder 24)
        Contains research material on Karp.
      - Yolande Karsenti (Medina), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Barbara and Paul Kayfetz, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Ted Kheel, 1991-1996 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Frits de Knegt, 1985-1993 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Josy Kraft, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Hilton Kramer, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 30)
        Contains research material on Kramer.
      - Jivka Langvad, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Hugh Levin, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Torsten Lilju, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Linde, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Albert Maysles, 1976-1995 (Box 7, Folder 35)
        Contains clippings and advertisements for the Maysles' films.
      - David Maysles, 1985-1992 (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - Mary Fuller McChesney, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Ole Henrik Moe, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Philipe de Montebello, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Swana Morenz, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - Priscilla Morgan, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 41)
      - Keiko Murata, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 42)
      - Yasuke Nakahara, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 43)
      - Howard Nemerovski, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 44)
      - Annina Nosei, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 45)
      - Claes Oldenburg, circa 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 46)
        Contains research material on Oldenburg.
      - Nam June Paik, circa 1988-1993 (Box 7, Folder 47)
        Contains research material only, no interview.
      - Lennart Preutz, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 48)
      - Pierre Restany, 1963; 1985-1995 (Box 7, Folder 49)
        Contains photographs from 1991 and 1995, photocopies of early Christo catalogs, research material, and a letter from Jacob Baal-Teshuva.
      - Harrison Rivera-Terreaux, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 50)
      - Larry Rivers, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - Barbara Rose, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 52)
      - Klaus-Henning Rosen, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Dieter Rosenkranz, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - Niki de Saint-Phalle, 1990-1996 (Box 7, Folder 55)
        Contains research material and photocopies of Harry Shunk photographs of 1961 gallery opening of Saint-Phalle exhibition.
      - Kazuhiko Satani, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - Sabine Saphörster, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 57)
      - Henry Scott-Stokes, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - George Segal, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Peter Selz, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 60)
      - Harry Shunk, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 61)
      - Holly Solomon, 1986-1994 (Box 7, Folder 62)
      - Illeana and Michael Sonnabend, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 63)
        Includes research material on the Sonnabends.
      - Katrin Specker, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 64)
      - Roland Specker, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 65)
        Contains a photograph of Specker.
      - Leo Steinberg, 1987-1993 (Box 7, Folder 66)
      - Saul Steinberg, 1967; 1987-1992 (Box 7, Folder 67)
        Contains 1967 exhibition catalog and clippings.
      - John Thompson, 1985-1995 (Box 7, Folder 68)
      - Anita Thorhaug, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 69)